Matthew Trentacoste

email: mt@matttrent.com 863

863 Florida St.

URL: http://matttrent.com

San Francisco, CA 94110

phone: +1.415.326.3226

Current position

Areas of specialization

Computer Scientist
Adobe, San Francisco

Computer vision, image processing, visual perception, cooking, kung fu

Synopsis

Ph.D. in image processing & computer vision. Experienced in technology development in academia and companies of all shapes and sizes. Interested in developing technology for awesome projects related to machine learning, computer vision and all things data.

Education

PHD in Computer Science, University of British Columbia

MSc in Computer Science, University of British Columbia

BSc in Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University

Professional Experience

2013-present Computer Scientist, Adobe, San Francisco, CA.

Handled majority of product management responsibilities for mobile photography project. Designed and implemented photo editting UI + underlying GPU image processing algorithms. Developing data pipelines for creative products.

Conducting research identifying and classifying visual style of images, as well as recommending content-specific edits.

2009-present Scientist, Empty Research, Vancouver, BC.

Multiple projects including computer vision and artificial intelligence algorithms for computational aesthetics, automatically generated websites for mobile devices, and GPU-accelerated mobile photography and vision applications.

2011-2012 Researcher / Developer, Pocket Pixels Inc., Vancouver, BC.

Top-selling selective desaturation photography for iPhone and iPad. Completely rebuilt the app's graphics framework, included interactive image adjustments and faster performance. After release, the app rose to #6 in the US store.

2007-2009 Research Engineer, Dolby Canada, Vancouver, BC.

Supported the development of Dolby technology licensed to manufacturers, including the SIM2 Grand Cinema SO-LAR. Developed calibration methods for accurate display of content on HDR displays, and environment sensing setups for adjusting display color to the viewing environment. Reduced visible artifacts from LED variation by 90%.

2004-2007 Principal Software Developer / Researcher, BrightSide Technologies, Vancouver, BC.

Responsible for the complete design, development, and implementation of a the video processing pipeline for LED-backlight display prototype, the BrightSide DR₃₇-P. Developed the GPU-accelerated software used for all demos, securing 2 years worth of investment capital. Created third-party API for display hardware. Expanded IP portfolio.

Publications & talks

JOURNAL ARTICLES & PAPERS

- Recognizing Image Style, S. Karayev, M. Trentacoste, H. Han, A. Agarwala, T. Darrell, A. Hertzmann, H. Winnemoeller. British Machine Vision Conf.
- Unsharp Masking, Countershading and Halos: Enhancements or Artifacts?, M. Trentacoste, R. Mantiuk, W. Heidrich, F. Dufrot. Eurographics
- Glare Encoding of High Dynamic Range Images, M. Rouf, R. Mantiuk, W. Heidrich, M. Trentacoste, C. Lau. CVPR
- Blur-Aware Image Downsampling, M. Trentacoste, R. Mantiuk, W. Heidrich. Eurographics
- Defocus Techniques for Camera Dynamic Range Expansion, M. Trentacoste, C. Lau, M. Rouf, R. Mantiuk, W. Heidrich. Proceedings. of Human Vision and Electronic Imaging XXI
- Photometric Image Processing for High Dynamic Range Displays, M. Trentacoste, W. Heidrich, L. Whitehead, H. Seetzen, G. Ward. Journal of Visual Communication and Image Representation, Special Issue on High Dynamic Range Imaging
- Ldr2Hdr: On-the-fly Reverse Tone Mapping of Legacy Video and Photographs, A. G. Rempel, M. Trentacoste, H. Seetzen, D. Young, W. Heidrich, L. Whitehead, G. Ward. Transactions on Graphics, SIGGRAPH
- Real Illumination from Virtual Environments, A. Ghosh, M. Trentacoste, H. Seetzen, and W. Heidrich. Eurographics Symposium on Rendering
- Volume Rendering for High Dynamic Range Displays, A. Ghosh, M. Trentacoste and W. Heidrich. International Workshop on Volume Graphics
- 2004 High Dynamic Range Display Systems, H. Seetzen, W. Heidrich, W. Stuerzlinger, G. Ward, L. Whitehead, M. Trentacoste, A. Ghosh, A. Vorozcovs. Transactions on Graphics, SIGGRAPH

PATENTS

- Mitigation of LCD Flare, G. Ward, J. Harrison, H. Seetzen, M. Trentacoste, US 2010/0277515
- Multiple Modulator Displays and Related Methods, W. Heidrich, M. Trentacoste, G. Ward, H. Seetzen, US 2010/0091045 A1

Other refereed contributions

- 2006 It's Tea Time!, K. Lemke, M. Trentacoste, A. Treuille, M. Goesele, W. Heidrich, B. Mones, SIG-GRAPH 2006 Teapot Exhibit
- Real Illumination from Virtual Environments, A. Ghosh, M. Trentacoste, H. Seetzen, and W. Heidrich, SIGGRAPH Sketch Program
- Tutorial on High Dynamic Range Techniques, M. Goesele, W. Heidrich, B. Hoefflinger, G. Krawczyk, K. Myszkowski, M. Trentacoste, Eurographics
- Sunnybrook Technologies HDR display demonstration, Sunnybrook Technologies, SIGGRAPH Emerging Technologies booth

TALKS

PyData NYC

2011

Bangor University, Adobe, Disney Research, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, NVIDIA

Thesis

PhD Manipulating Scale-Dependent Perception of Images

Evaluation of how the perceptual of blur and contrast depends on the scale at which image features are represented in the human visual system and several algorithms that leverage this understanding to alter image appearance.

MSc Photometric Image Processing for High Dynamic Range Displays

Techniques for the calibration and processing images for display on new high dynamic range display devices for reproducing photometrically accurate images.

Honors Implementing Performance Numerical Libraries on Graphics Hardware

A simple method to implement floating-point vector math operations and matrix multiplication on graphics hardware, identifying performance characteristics of hardware and softare.

Skills

Experienced in both academic research and product development. Significant image processing experience, including GPU-based. Programming languages are many, with an emphasis on C-variants & Python. Background in visual perception, experienced photographer. World-travelling vagabond, comfortable living out of a suitcase. Bio-hacker, well-versed in experimentation and self-programming. Amateur chef. Martial artist. Avant-gardener.

References

Ask and ye shall receive.